你们好，美丽的人们，Linux真正令人惊叹的一点是，几乎所有的东西
Hello you beautiful people so one really amazing thing about Linux is the way that pretty much everything
可以将系统上的文件视为一个文件。
on the system can be treated as a file.
我早些时候看到了这一点，当时我们表演了一个非常棒的魔术，它会将数据从一个
And I saw this earlier when we did the totally awesome magic trick will be redirected data from one
终端连接到另一个终端，这是可能的，因为Linux将终端作为文件处理
terminal to the other and that was possible because the terminal was treated as a file by the Linux
操作系统，并且可以在系统上的设备之间重定向数据，就像您可以重定向数据一样
operating system and can redirect data between devices on your system just like you can redirect data
在文件之间。
between files.
现在，系统上的每个文件都位于一个称为Linux文件系统树的结构上。
Now every one of the files on the system is on a structure known as the Linux file system tree.
在这段视频中，您将了解Linux文件系统是如何构建的，您还将
And in this video you're going to learn how the Linux file system is structured and you're also going
了解文件系统中一些最重要的位置。
to get a tour of what some of the most important places on the file system are.
可以说，在视频结束时，你就会知道这片土地的地图了。
By the end of the video you'll know the map of the land so to speak.
通过了解您实际导航的内容和布局，您将做好更好的准备
And by knowing what you're actually navigating and how it's laid out you'll be much better prepared
才能真正导航和修改它。
to actually navigate it and modify it.
这就是我们将在下一个视频中开始学习的内容。
And that's what we'll start learning in the next video.
因此，您将了解计算机上的一些非常重要的位置，因此还将了解哪些位置
So you're going to learn about some very important locations on your computer and also therefore which
将帮助你在这个视频中更好地导航真正令人敬畏的东西，伙计们。
will help you navigate even better loads of really awesome stuff in this video guys.
所以，让我们继续下去，开始吧。
So let's go ahead and get into it.
您需要知道的第一件事是，整个Linux文件系统都遵循树形结构。
The first thing you need to know is that the entire Linux file system follows a tree structure.
因此，如果您的硬盘上没有分区，则可以在一个分区中访问系统上的所有内容
So if there's no partitions on your hard drive every single thing on the system can be accessed in one
高大的树形结构。
large tree structure.
那么让我们继续来看看吧。
So let's go ahead and take a look at it.
以下是文件系统外观的图像。
Here's an image of what the file system looks like.
现在，在树的顶部，我们有所谓的根目录，这里由劈开表示。
Now at the top of the tree we have what we call the root directory represented by the slash here.
现在我说目录这个词的时候，我只是想澄清一下，如果你以前没有遇到过这个词的话
Now just to be clear in case you haven't come across the word before when I say the word directory I
基本上就是指“文件夹”这个词。
basically just mean the word folder.
好的，所以当我说根目录时，我只是指的是文件系统上的根文件夹。
OK so when I say a root directory I'm just referring to the root folder on the file system.
这里的劈开现在将该文件夹称为根目录，因为文件系统上的所有内容都可以
The slash here now that folder is called the root directory because everything on the file system can
可以追溯到这一点。
be traced back to that.
就像树上的每一根树枝和树叶都可以追溯到树根。
Just like every branch and leaf on a tree can be traced back to the root of the tree.
现在，在根目录下有一大堆其他目录，这些目录称为
Now under that root directory there's a whole bunch of other directories these directories are said
作为根目录的子目录。
to be subdirectories of the root directory.
换句话说，根目录是所有这些目录的父目录。
Another way to say that is that the root directory is the parent directory for all of these directories.
这里用橙色表示，现在您的系统上可能有更多的文件夹或目录，但我已将
In orange here now there may be more folders or directories present on your system but I've taken the
最重要的是要在这张图中显示，因为一张幻灯片只有这么大的空间。
most important ones to show here in this image because a slide only has so much space.
现在，这些目录中的每个目录都可以包含其中的所有目录和文件以及目录
Now each of these directories can have all the directories and files inside of them and the directories
在这些目录中，可以有它们自己的目录和文件等等。
inside those directories can have their own directories and files and so on and so on and so on.
因此，整个系统最终看起来确实像一棵真正的大树，有成百上千的树枝。
So the whole system does eventually look like a really big tree with hundreds and hundreds of branches.
现在，此树上最重要的目录之一是主目录包含的主目录
Now one of the most important directories on this tree is the home directory the home directory holds
系统上每个不同常规用户的单独目录。
individual directories for each of the different regular users on the system.
我们可以看到，该系统有三个固定用户。
We can see that the system has three regular users.
我们有Alice、Bob和Charlie，每个用户都可以有自己的文件。
We've got Alice Bob and Charlie and each of those users can have their own files.
例如，如果我们以Bob为例，我们可以看到Bob在其桌面的主目录中有文件夹
So for example if we take Bob we can see the Bob has folders in the home directory for their desktop
文档、下载音乐、图片等等。
documents downloads music pictures and so on.
这些文件夹中的每一个都可以有文件和文件夹，爱丽丝将具有类似的结构
And each of those folders can have files and folders inside them Alice will have a similar structure
查理也会的。
and so will Charlie.
您可以通过单击此处的此文件图标来访问您的主目录。
You can access your home directory by clicking on this file's icon over here.
默认打开的将是您的主目录。
And what opens up by default will be your home directory.
到目前为止，我们在课程中所做的一切，只是在玩弄管道的重定向
Now everything that we've been doing in the course up until now so just playing with pipeline's redirection
所有这些文件都在我们的主目录中，您可以
and stuff and creating files they've all those files have all been in our home directory and you can
您可以看到，在我们的主目录中，我们有一个桌面、文档、下载音乐、图片等等
see that in our home directory We have a desktop documents downloads music pictures and so on and so
就像鲍勃在图中所做的那样。
on just like Bob did in the diagram.
如果您正在浏览您的文件系统，您可以随时通过以下方式返回到您的主目录
And if you are navigating around your file system you can always get back to your home directory by
单击此处的主页图标，或在您可以想到的顶部路径中找到它
clicking on this home icon here or by finding it in the path that appears at the top you can think of
文件系统上的所有内容都分为两个主要部分。
everything on the file system as being in two major parts.
这有点过于简单化了，但是您可以想到Users主文件夹下的所有内容
And this is a bit of an oversimplification but you can think of everything below the users home folder
因为它是特定于该用户的。
as being specific to that user.
用户主文件夹上方的所有内容都会影响整个系统。
And everything that's above the users home folder tending to affect the whole system.
现在，如果普通用户可以修改甚至删除整个系统所需的文件，那会有什么好处呢
Now what good would it be if regular users could modify or even delete files that the whole system requires
去跑步。
to run.
一点也不好。
Not very good at all.
这就是为什么倾向于影响整个系统的特殊文件和文件夹通常需要提升
And that's why special files and folders that tend to affect the whole system usually require elevated
管理员或root权限。
administrator or root privileges.
系统上的root用户类似于Linux上Windows中的管理员。
The root user on the system is similar to the administrator in windows on Linux.
root用户拥有对整个系统的绝对权限。
The root user has absolute power over the entire system.
现在，我将在后面的视频中向您展示如何执行root用户的操作。
Now I'll show you how you can perform actions of the root user in a later video.
但就目前而言，只要意识到它们的存在就行了。
But for now just be aware of their existence.
现在，我只想讨论顶部的这些文件夹有什么作用。
For now I just want to discuss what these folders at the top here do.
现在有很多这样的人。
Now there's a lot of them.
为了避免您记住，我做了一个小抄，您可以从参考资料部分下载
So to save you from memorizing I've made a cheat sheet that you can download from the resources section
在这次演讲中。
in this lecture.
现在让我们一起来看一看吧。
Let's go ahead and go through it together now.
好的，就像我说的，你可以从这段视频的参考资料部分得到这张小抄的副本
OK so as I said you can get a copy of this cheat sheet from the resources section in this video and
它基本上包含的是根目录正下方的不同文件夹的列表
what it basically contains is a list of the different folders that are right underneath the root directory
使用劈开编写，并对它们的功能进行了一些描述，以便您可以了解更多
written with a slash and a bit of a description about what they do so that you can have a bit more of
了解每个文件夹在系统中的作用。
an understanding of what each of the folders does on your system.
让我们快速浏览一下它们，然后您可以稍后更详细地了解它
Let's just do a quick whistle stop tour of each of them and then you can look at it later in more detail
为了你自己。
for yourself.
好的。
OK.
所以我们可以把劈开目录放大一点，把它放大一点。
So we've got the slash directory to zoom in a little bit make it make the thing a bit bigger.
我们走吧。
There we go.
这样您就得到了劈开目录，它是工厂的最顶层或根目录，还有这个目录
So you've got the slash directory which is the very top or the root of the factory and this directory
里面有其他所有东西，没有什么比劈开目录更高的了。
holds everything else there is nothing higher up than the slash directory.
如果你到了这里，你就到了树的最顶端。
If you get here you are at the very top of the tree.
您已经获得了bin目录，其中存储了常用的Linux用户命令BINARY。B.N BINARY是Ben获得的位置
You've got the bin directory which stores common Linux user command binary b.n binary is where Ben gets
它的名称来自例如DATE命令。
its name from for example the date command.
来吧，现在所有存储在二进制文件中的命令都是二进制文件夹中的性别。
Come on now commands that are all stored in the binary is sex in the binary folder.
您已经获得了引导文件夹boot用于引导系统所需的所有内容，因此可引导Linux
You've got the boot folder boot is for everything that is required to boot the system so bootable linux
dev文件夹上的内核和引导加载程序配置文件。
kernel and boot loader configuration files over the dev folder.
这就是代表设备的文件。
So this is these are files representing devices.
现在该文件夹中有许多不同的文件。
Now there's many different files in that folder.
如果文件名以T.T.开头，为什么那是一个终端。
If the filename starts with T.T. why that's a terminal.
如果它也和F.D.在一起，那就是一张软盘。
If it's also with F.D. that's a floppy disk.
如果它以SD或海地开头，那就是硬盘。
If it's starts with SD or Haiti that's a hard disk.
如果它从RAM开始，那么它就是RAM，如果它也是CD，那么它就是CD-ROM。
If it starts with RAM then it's RAM and if it's also a CD then it's a CD-ROM.
您有劈开ATC，它是管理配置文件。
You've got slash ATC which is administrative configuration files.
通常所说的没有ATC或ETSI是非常常见的文件夹。
No ATC or ETSI as it's normally said is a very common folder.
如果您想要编辑配置文件以及如何编辑这些配置，您会经常使用它
You'll be using it a lot if you ever want to edit configuration files and how you edit those configuration
文件是Linux手册第5节发挥作用的地方。
files is where Section 5 of the Linux manual comes into play.
这都是关于文件格式之类的内容，因此用于编辑许多配置文件
Which is all about file formats and things like that so for editing many of the configuration files
在ETSI文件夹中，您将能够找到一个手册页，该手册页将向您展示如何执行此操作。
are in the ETSI folder you'll be able to find a man page that'll show you how to do it.
然后您就得到了主文件夹，主文件夹就是主目录所在的位置。
Then you've got the home folder and the home folder is where the home directory is.
对于常规用户，存储在主文件夹下，因此每个不同的用户都有一个主目录
For regular users are stored so under the home folder you have a home directory for each of the different
这样的用户，比如说我在劈开家里就有一个，劈开子牙。
users so for example I have one at slash home slash Ziyad.
我的主文件夹在大的主目录中，所以如果我的计算机上还有另外3个人，名为
I have my home folder inside the big home directory so if I had 3 other people on my computer called
爱丽丝·鲍勃和查理他们会是劈开家劈开和劈开家劈开鲍勃劈开劈开查理。
Alice Bob and Charlie they'd be slash home slash and slash home slash Bob slash slash Charlie.
但对我来说，劈开、劈开、孜亚德就行了。
But in my case just slash slash Ziyad.
这就是您的主目录存储在主文件夹中的位置。
So that's where your home directory is stored in the home folder.
您有Slush介质，这是我们Stick等可移动介质的外置硬盘驱动器
You've got slushed media which is where removable media such as us be stick's external hard drives and
与硬盘驱动器(如实际硬盘)不同的是，已挂载的东西和可从系统中移除的任何东西都是可移除的
things are mounted and anything that is removable from the system unlike hard drives like actual hard
驱动器。
drives.
任何可拆卸的东西通常都会挂载到劈开媒体劈开库中，因此共享库就在这里
Anything that's removable usually gets mounted on slash media slash lib is where shared libraries so
LIB是Slush业务中的应用程序所需的库的缩写，用于引导Espen文件夹
lib being short for libraries needed by applications in the slush business last Espen folders to boot
这个系统。
the system.
这就是所有东西都加载的地方，基本上就是装入的东西，因为这是劈开库
So this is where all that stuff is all loaded basically loads of installed stuff cause it's slash lib
劈开。
slash.
MT是一个挂载外部设备的地方，您不经常使用它。
MT is a place to mount external devices you don't use it that often.
通常使用劈开媒体代替劈开杂项。
Usually slash media is used instead slash misc.
杂项的缩写是我们有时用来自动化文件系统的一个控制器，它就在那里
Being short for miscellaneous is a director we use to sometimes automate filesystems it's just there
以防系统可以使用它。
just in case the system can use it.
劈开欧佩克或OPT.是您可以存储附加软件或换句话说可选软件的位置。
Slash OPEC or Opt. is where you can store additional or in other words optional software.
所以你安装的任何东西，你安装的任何程序，通常都会把文件放在劈开的O.P.到劈开
So anything that you install any programs that you install usually the files go in slash O.P. to slash
PROK是关于系统资源的，更多的是管理性的东西，劈开路由。
prok is about system resources as more administrative kind of stuff slash route.
现在，这是root用户的主文件夹。
Now this is the home folder for the root user.
所以这有时也是念力的一个要点。
So this is sometimes a point of confusion.
你有一个屋顶文件夹，也就是劈开，有时也叫劈开目录，还有劈开
You've got the roof folder which is the slash sometimes called the slash directory and you've got slash
根目录和劈开根目录是根用户的主文件夹。
root and slash root is the home folder for the root user.
所以这是一个有点令人困惑的术语，但只要记住这一点就行了。
So it's a bit of a confusing terminology but just just bear in Bear that in mind.
好的，劈开是根目录。
OK the slash is the root directory.
它位于文件树的最顶端，劈开路径是超级用户或超级用户的主文件夹
It is the very top of the file tree and slash route is the home folder for the root user or the super
用户或管理员。
user or the administrator.
类似的城市管理员如果您使用的是Windows，这几乎是管理员的主目录
Similar city administrator if you are on Windows that's the home directory for the administrator almost
现在您已经有了slush Espen，它包含管理命令，或者Beiner是
there now you've got slush Espen which contains administrative administrative commands or Beiner is
对于root或超级用户。
for the root or super user.
因此，Espen作为超级用户使用二进制文件是可以的，因此这些命令可以由超级用户或
So Espen being super use a binary is OK so these are commands that can be run by the super user or the
root用户。
root user.
你得到了斜杠的VMP，它包含由应用程序运行的临时文件，有时当程序
You've got slashed VMP which contains temporary files run by applications sometimes when programs are
运行时，它们会创建临时文件以提高运行效率。
running they create temporary files to make them more efficient to run.
那是那些东西存放的地方。
That's where those are stored.
DMP文件夹通常非常定期地清空，或者在程序关闭时清除我们的最后一个用户
The DMP folders usually cleared out very regularly or when the program's shut slushing us our last user
包含与用户有关的文件，这些文件理论上在安装后不会更改，劈开变量包含
contains files pertaining to users that in theory don't change after installation and slash var contains
可变数据的目录或变化很大的数据。
directories of variable data or data that changes a lot.
例如，系统日志文件通常位于此处和日志文件中
That can be used by various So for example system log files are usually found in here and log files
改变了很多。
change a lot.
这就是为什么他们在劈开或劈开变量中，劈开变量是变量的缩写。
That's why they're in the slash or slash variable slash var being short for variable.
它们是不同的文件夹。
So they are these are the different folders.
仅有的(至少是最常见的)直接位于劈开文件夹下面的文件，请看一下
The only at least the most common ones that are directly underneath the slash folder so have a look
在这个时候，杰驰再读一遍，你知道，也许是用我的视频，用我的声音播放
at this Jiechi read through it once again and you know maybe with my video with my voice playing in
背景你不需要记住这个。
the background you don't have to memorize this.
那里的便宜座位，以防你不需要记住这些东西，你很快就会熟悉的
The cheap seats there just in case you don't have to memorize this stuff you very quickly become familiar
用你会用到的最常用的。
with the most common ones that you'll use.
最有可能的是，您只会坚持使用ETSI，在ETSI中，配置文件是主文件夹，
Most likely you'll just stick to using ETSI which is where configuration files are the home folder and
可能是媒体(如果您插入usp驱动器或类似的设备)，也可能是劈开用户(如果您愿意
maybe media if you plug in a USP drive or something like that and maybe slash user if you want to and
这跟节目有关。
it's something to do with programs.
但通常情况下，这些是你将会遇到的最常见的问题，但你会变得非常熟悉
But usually those are the most common ones you'll be you'll be dealing with but you'll become very familiar
文件所在的位置。
at where files are.
在整个课程中，我们将使用大量这些不同的文件夹，或者不要担心是否全部使用这些文件夹
We'll be using a lot of these different folders as we go through the course or don't worry if it all
看起来有点像我们现在就知道信息永远都在那里。
seems like a bit we're right now that information is there forever.
拿着就行，一步一步来。
Just take it take it one step at a time.
不要被它压得喘不过气来。
Don't be overwhelmed by it.
天气会好起来的，你很快就会习惯的。
It's going to be fine and you'll very quickly become accustomed to it.
好的，现在你就知道了。
OK so there you have it.
现在您应该对Linux文件系统及其结构有了更好的理解。
You should now have a much better understanding of the Linux file system and how it's structured.
因此，作为快速回顾，我们讨论了Linux文件系统遵循树状结构，从
So as a quick recap we discussed that the Linux file system follows a tree like structure starting at
以劈开为代表的基目录。
a base directory which is represented by the slash.
现在，您可以将文件系统上的所有内容都追溯到该基目录。
Now you lumber everything on the file system can be traced back to that base directory.
您还了解到，HLN NEXT系统上有一个特殊用户，称为root用户，该root用户是
You also learned that there's a special user on HLN next system called the root user the root user is
与Windows上的管理员类似，root用户拥有对整个系统的绝对权限。
similar to the administrator on Windows and the root user has absolute power over the entire system.
他们可以做任何他们想做的事。
They can do anything that they want.
您了解到主目录或劈开主目录包含以下项的各个主目录
You learn that the home directory or the slash home directory holds individual home directories for
系统上的所有常规用户，以便他们有地方存储他们的个人文件。
all the regular users on the system so that they have a place to store their personal files.
并且您将了解到劈开路由文件夹是管理员的根用户的主目录。
And you learn that the slash route folder is the home directory for the root user for the administrator.
您还必须查看一组非常重要的文件夹，这些文件夹就在基本目录的正下方
You also have to look at a bunch of really important folders that are right underneath the base directory
您可以在参考资料部分下载一份小抄。
and there's a cheat sheet that you can download in the resources section.
好的，所有这些信息都汇总给您了。
Well all that information is summarized for you.
好的。
OK.
非常棒，让您了解文件系统的整个结构，它完全是史诗般的
Brilliant so that you understand the whole structure of the file system which is totally epic in its
这是你自己的权利。
own right.
我还在参考资料部分放置了一系列博客文章的链接，以了解有关Linux的更多信息
I've also put a link to a series of blog posts in the resources section to learn more about the Linux
文件系统。
file system.
如果您愿意，但现在我们将继续使用命令行开始导航
If you want to but for now we're going to go ahead and jump into using the command line to start navigating
文件系统将会非常激动人心。
the file system which is going to be really exciting.
好了，我会在下一个视频中见到你。
So for all that goodness I'll see you in the next video.